Guide to the Melville Cane Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Hayden, Hiram "Athwart, We Beg You", [Philadelphia?], 16 April 1969, (1 page t.ms.s. (poem)) (Box 2)
    [Also signed by Melville Cane, Helen Wolf, William Jovanovich, et al.]
  - Hayden, Hiram "Presence of Cane", [New York], 15 April 1971, (1 page t.ms.s. (poem)) (Box 2)
    [Also signed by Melville Cane, Helen Wolff, William Jovanovich, et al.]
  - Hayden, Hiram "To Cane, on being ninety-three", [Philadelphia?], 15 April 1972, (1 page printed poem (3 copies, signed by the author; 1 copy, framed, dated "4/20/72" and signed by Cane)) (Box 2)
    [One copy of the poem printed on different paper, signed by the author, with envelope with a.n. by Melville Cane; SHELVED IN MAP CASE 14-13-10.]
  - [Lincoln, Abraham] A writ of capias by Stuart & Lincoln; in the hand of John Todd Stuart (?), Sangamon Co., IL, [3 May 1839], (1 page ms.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - [Moore, Marianne] "The Storm", [New York], n.d., (1 page t.d. (poem)) (Box 2)
    [A.n. by Cane on his poem, "The Storm is broken"]
  - Morley, Christopher "Midsummer pause: the telephone's talked out...", Roslyn Heights, NY, [ca. 1950?], (1 page t.d.s. (s. with initials)) (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton "Poetry and personality: an appreciation of Melville Cane", n.p., [Dec 1951], (17 pages t.ms.) (Box 5)
    [With corrections in the author's hand]
  - Sinclair, Mary Craig Kimbrough (Mrs. Upton) "Heart Attack", Monrovia, CA, ca. May 1955, (1 page t.ms.s. (poem)) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan "The Sage", n.p., 17 May 1944, (1 page t.ms.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan "The Viennese ladies", n.p., [1952], (2 pages t.ms.s. (inscribed to Melville Cane)) (Box 6)
  - White, Elwyn Brooks "Response", n.p., n.d., (1 page t.ms.s. (poem to Melville Cane, s. with initials)) (Box 6)
- Series III: Arranged Correspondence
  - Academy of American Poets (Box 7)
  - Accent (Box 7)
  - Adams, Franklin P. (Box 7)
  - Adams, J. Donald (Box 7)
  - Adams, Leonie (Box 7)
  - Alden, Add (Box 7)
  - Allen, Frederick L. (Box 7)
  - Allen, William D. (Box 7)
  - Alsberg, H.G. (Box 7)
  - Altman, Harold (Box 7)
  - Amberg, Martin L. (Box 7)
  - American Book Publishers Council (Box 7)
  - American Heritage (Box 7)
  - American Literary Association (Box 7)
  - American Scholar (Hiram Haydn) (Box 7)
  - Amstutz, Edward A. (Box 7)
  - Anderson, Karl (Box 7)
  - Anker, Judy (Box 7)
  - Antioch Review (Box 7)
  - Aspen Poetry Workshop (Box 7)
  - Aswell, Edward C. (Box 7)
  - Athenean (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Monthly (Box 7)
  - Atwood, Jane (Box 7)
  - Auslander, Joseph (Box 7)
  - Avery, Lee (Box 7)
  - Bacon, Peggy (Box 7)
  - Barr, Stringfellow (Box 7)
  - Barranger, Miriam G. (Box 7)
  - Bean, Marshall E. (Box 7)
  - Benet, William Rose (Box 7)
  - Benjamin, John (Box 7)
  - Bernstein, Aline (Box 7)
  - Blossom, Sumner (Box 7)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company (Box 7)
  - Bode, Carl (Box 7)
  - Bookman, The (Box 7)
  - Boston University (Box 7)
  - Bower, Jack (Box 7)
  - Bower, Warren (Box 7)
  - Bowes, Edward (Box 7)
  - Bracker, Jon (Box 7)
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall (Box 7)
  - Bronk, Detlev W. (Box 7)
  - Brooklyn Poetry Circle (Box 7)
  - Brooks, Eleanor (Box 7)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 7)
  - Brown, John Mason (Box 7)
  - Brown, Ruth (Box 7)
  - Brumbaugh, T.B. (Box 7)
  - Brunini, John G. (Box 7)
  - Bryson, Lyman (Box 7)
  - Buchman, Marion (Box 7)
  - Buffalo, University of (Box 7)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Box 7)
  - Butterfield, Frances (Box 7)
  - "Camera Three" (Box 7)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel (Box 7)
  - Cappon, Alexander (Box 7)
  - Carlisle, Thomas John (Box 7)
  - Carmer, Carl (Box 7)
  - Carpenter, Margaret (Box 7)
  - Century Magazine (Box 7)
  - Cerf, Bennett (Box 7)
  - Chase, Lewis (Box 7)
  - Ciardi, John (Box 7)
  - Clark, Robert K. (Box 7)
  - Cohn, Alfred E. (Box 7)
  - Cold Springs Institute (Box 7)
  - Colum, Padraic (Box 7)
  - Columbia Review (Box 7)
  - Columbia University (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Alumni Federation (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Club (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Forum (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Libraries (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Oral History (Box 7)
  - Columbia University Quarterly (Box 7)
  - Commentary (Box 7)
  - Commonweal, The (Box 7)
  - Conkey, Albert B. (Box 7)
  - Contempo (Box 7)
  - Cook, J. Frederick (Box 7)
  - Coda, Wadlyn D. (Box 7)
  - Cox, Alice (Box 7)
  - Cox, Esther Ann (Box 7)
  - Cox, Sidney (Box 7)
  - Coykendall, Frederick (Box 7)
  - Cozzens, James Gould (Box 7)
  - Cross, Wilbur (Box 7)
  - Curley, Agnes V. (Box 7)
  - Cushing, Charles C. (Box 7)
  - Dangerfield, George (Box 8)
  - Davidson, Gustav (Box 8)
  - Davis, Lambert (Box 8)
  - Davison, Edward (Box 8)
  - Davison, Charles B. (Box 8)
  - Day, Katharine (Box 8)
  - Decker, Clarence R. (Box 8)
  - DeForest, Henry P. (Box 8)
  - Delza, Elizabeth (Box 8)
  - Denny, George V. (Box 8)
  - Deutsch, Babette (Box 8)
  - Devin-Adair Company (Box 8)
  - DeYoung, Lynden E. (Box 8)
  - Dial, The (Box 8)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company (Box 8)
  - Dollard, Charles (Box 8)
  - Dorn, Alfred (Box 8)
  - Downtown Gallery (Box 8)
  - Doxtator, Richard (Box 8)
  - Doyle, Joseph (Box 8)
  - Durham, Knowlton (Box 8)
  - Dutton, E.P., and Company (Box 8)
  - Eaton, Evelyn (Box 8)
  - Eberhart, Richard (Box 8)
  - Edman, Irwin (Box 8)
  - Einbinder, Harvey (Box 8)
  - Einstein, Lewis (Box 8)
  - Eiseley, Loren C. (Box 8)
  - Ellison, James (Box 8)
  - Emond, Florence (Box 8)
  - Ennery, Katherine (Box 8)
  - Ernst, Bernard M.L. (Box 8)
  - Erskine, John (Box 8)
  - Esquire (Box 8)
  - Fackenthal, Frnak Diehl (Box 8)
  - Fantasy (Box 8)
  - Fetter, Paul (Box 8)
  - Fetter, David J. (Box 8)
  - Field, Andrew (Box 8)
  - Flaecus, Kimball (Box 8)
  - Flagler, Harry Harkness (Box 8)
  - Flagler, Jack M. (Box 8)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (Box 8)
  - Frankenberg, Lloyd (Box 8)
  - French, Katherine (Box 8)
  - Frost, Robert (Box 8)
  - Fuller, Muriel (Box 8)
  - Fuson, Ben W. (Box 8)
  - Gannett, Lewis (Box 8)
  - Garrett, Eileen J. (Box 8)
  - Gazzoli, Beatrice (Box 8)
  - Gibbs, Wolcott (Box 8)
  - Gilbert, Douglas (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Jeannette L. (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Joseph B. (Box 8)
  - Ginsberg, Louis (Box 8)
  - Goldman Eric F. (Box 8)
  - Good Housekeeping (Box 8)
  - Goodman, Mae Winkler (Box 8)
  - Grace, William J. (Box 8)
  - Graham, Arthur Butler (Box 8)
  - Gray, Douly (Box 8)
  - Greenslet, Ferris (Box 8)
  - Gregory, Will (Box 8)
  - Grendon, Felix (Box 8)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 8)
  - Gurney, Mrs. John (Box 8)
  - Gurney, Lawrence (Box 8)
  - Gurewich, Vladimir (Box 8)
  - Haberman, Helen (Box 8)
  - Hand, Learned (Box 8)
  - Harcourt, Alfred (Box 8)
  - Harcourt, Ellen (Box 8)
  - Harcourt, Brace & Company (Box 8)
  - Harper's Magazine (Box 8)
  - Harrison, Julian C. (Box 8)
  - Haselmayer, Louis M. (Box 8)
  - Hawkes, H.E. (Box 8)
  - Hawkins, Maude M. (Box 8)
  - Haydn, Hiram (Box 8)
  - Hecht, Celia (Box 8)
  - Hellman, Geoffrey (Box 8)
  - Helzberg, Gladys (Box 8)
  - Hepnor, Arthur W. (Box 8)
  - Horzberg, Max J. (Box 8)
  - Hill, Hyacinthe (Box 8)
  - Hilliard, Margaret (Box 8)
  - Hillyer, Robert (Box 8)
  - Hirsch, Dorothy (Box 8)
  - Hoffman, Isidor B. (Box 8)
  - Holmes, Doris (Mrs. John) (Box 8)
  - Holstein, M. (Box 8)
  - Holtzman, Fanny (Box 8)
  - Houghton, Elizabeth (McCall) (Box 8)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company (Box 8)
  - Howard, Frances (Box 8)
  - Hubbard, Elbert (Box 8)
  - Huebsch, Benfamin W. (Box 8)
  - Hyman, Mrs. Mark (Box 8)
  - Indiana University (Box 9)
  - Isaacs, Edith (Mrs. Stanley M.) (Box 9)
  - Ivins, William M. (Box 9)
  - Jack, Peter M. (Box 9)
  - Jackson, A.V. Williams (Box 9)
  - Johnson, A.E. (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Alvin (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Elaine (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Thomas H. (Box 9)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford (Box 9)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav (Box 9)
  - Kahn, Hannah (Box 9)
  - Kaufmann, Helen L. (Box 9)
  - Kellock, Harold (Box 9)
  - Kennedy, Foster (Box 9)
  - Kennedy, Richard (Box 9)
  - Kent, Katharine (Box 9)
  - Kentucky, University of (Box 9)
  - Keppel, F.P. (Box 9)
  - Killian, J.R. (Box 9)
  - Kirchwey, Freda (Box 9)
  - Kirk, Grayson (Box 9)
  - Kirsch, Lucille (Mrs. Neville) (Box 9)
  - Knickerbocker, William S. (Box 9)
  - Knox, John Clark (Box 9)
  - Kreuzberg, Harold (Box 9)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred (Box 9)
  - Kru, Ethel (Box 9)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Box 9)
  - LaFollette, Fola (Box 9)
  - LaFollette, Suzanne (Box 9)
  - Lamont, Hammond (Box 9)
  - Lane, Bent (Mrs. Clayton) (Box 9)
  - Laughlin, James (Box 9)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard (Box 9)
  - Learoyd, Harold J. (Box 9)
  - Ledoux, Louis V. (Box 9)
  - Lenox, Walter (Box 9)
  - Library of Congress (Box 9)
  - Life (Box 9)
  - Link, S. Gordden (Box 9)
  - Lippincott, J.B., Company (Box 9)
  - List, Kurt (Box 9)
  - Literary Review (Fairleigh Dickinson Univ.) (Box 9)
  - Loomis, Charles BaHell (Box 9)
  - Loveman, Amy (Box 9)
  - Leubge, William J. (Box 9)
  - Lyons, Gerald (Box 9)
  - Maas, Willard (Box 9)
  - Macauley, Pobie (Box 9)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret (Box 9)
  - McCall's (Box 9)
  - McCallum, John Hamilton (Box 9)
  - McCarthy, Margaret J. (Box 9)
  - McCook, Philip J. (Box 9)
  - McDaniels, J.H. (Box 9)
  - McHugh, Vincent (Box 9)
  - McKenny, Margaret (Box 9)
  - Mackinnon, Robert (Box 9)
  - Macleod, Norman (Box 9)
  - Manning, Edith B. (Box 9)
  - Marcus, Lawrence (Box 9)
  - Marcus, Paul (Box 9)
  - Marcus, Robert (Box 9)
  - Margolin, Sydney G. (Box 9)
  - Markham, Virgil (Box 9)
  - Marx, Anne (Box 9)
  - Mary Ildephonse, Sister (Box 9)
  - Mason, Mary L. (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts Review (Box 9)
  - Matthews, Elva de P. (Box 9)
  - Matthiessen, Francis Otto (Box 9)
  - Mauldin, Bill (Box 9)
  - Maxon, Constance (Box 9)
  - Mayes, Herbert R. (Box 9)
  - Mayfield, John S. (Box 9)
  - Mencham, Harry (Box 9)
  - Meisel, Frederic H. (Box 9)
  - Meloney, Marie Mattingly (Box 9)
  - Menorah Journal (Box 9)
  - Merriam, H.G. (Box 9)
  - Meyerhof, Monique (Box 9)
  - Meyerson, Edward (Box 9)
  - Mill, Dorothy (Box 9)
  - Miller, James (Box 9)
  - Miller, Mildred (Box 9)
  - Mitchell, E.P. (Box 9)
  - Moggach, Mrs. George (Box 9)
  - Monroe, Harriet (Box 9)
  - Moolten, Sylvan E. (Box 9)
  - Moore, Douglas (Box 9)
  - Morley, Christopher (Box 9)
  - Morley, Frank V. (Box 9)
  - Morse, Samuel (Box 9)
  - Muller, Elsie F. (Box 9)
  - Muhlert, Jan Keene (Box 9)
  - Murphy, B.W. (Box 9)
  - Mumsey's Magazine (Box 9)
  - Munson, Corham (Box 9)
  - Mumford, Lewis and Sophie (Box 9)
  - Museum of the City of New York (Box 9)
  - Nash, Ogden (Box 10)
  - Nation, The (Box 10)
  - New York Evening Post (Box 10)
  - New York Herald Tribune (Box 10)
  - New York Times (Box 10)
  - New York Typographical Union No. 6 (Box 10)
  - New Yorker, The (Box 10)
  - Nichol, Louise Townsend (Box 10)
  - Nock, Albert Jay (Box 10)
  - Norman, Dorothy (Box 10)
  - Odell, George C.D. (Box 10)
  - Oler, J. Wesley (Box 10)
  - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey (Box 10)
  - Orage, A.R. (Box 10)
  - Oregon, University of (Box 10)
  - Ornstein, Paul W. (Box 10)
  - P.E.N. (Box 10)
  - Parker, James Reid (Box 10)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey (Box 10)
  - Patri, Angelo (Box 10)
  - Paul, Sherman (Box 10)
  - Pauth, Nadja O. (Box 10)
  - Pearce, Charles A. (Box 10)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes (Box 10)
  - Phantasmus (Box 10)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 10)
  - Philadelphia Guardian (Box 10)
  - Placzek, Adolf (Box 10)
  - Poet Lore (Box 10)
  - "Poetry Awards" (Box 10)
  - Poetry Center (YM-YWHA) (Box 10)
  - Poetry Center of America (Box 10)
  - Poetry Center of Texas (Box 10)
  - Poetry Center of Virginia (Box 10)
  - Pottle, Frederick A. (Box 10)
  - Powell, Lyman (Box 10)
  - Powers, Marcella (Box 10)
  - Prairie Schooner (Box 10)
  - Proskauer, Joseph M. (Box 10)
  - Proskauer, Richard (Box 10)
  - Public Affairs Press (Box 10)
  - Puck (Box 10)
  - Puck, Theodore T. (Box 10)
  - Pulitzer Prizes (Box 10)
  - Pullen, G.F. (Box 10)
  - Pulling, Edward (Box 10)
  - Punch (Box 10)
  - Rahy, Philip (Box 10)
  - Rand, Ayn (Box 10)
  - Random House (Box 10)
  - Rago, Henry (Box 10)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 10)
  - Raphael, Alice (Box 10)
  - Raphael, Robert (Box 10)
  - Rawlins, Winifred (Box 10)
  - Reader's Digest (Box 10)
  - Reynolds, Virginia D. (Box 10)
  - Roberts, W. Adolphe (Box 10)
  - Robinson, Anthony (Box 10)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton (Box 10)
  - Rocky Mountain Review (Box 10)
  - Rodgers, Richard (Box 10)
  - Rogers, W.G. (Box 10)
  - Rosenberg, James N. (Box 10)
  - Ross, David (Box 10)
  - Rons, Peyton (Box 10)
  - Rowlands, Peggy (Box 10)
  - Rubin, Jean (Box 10)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 10)
  - Salomon, I.L. (Box 10)
  - Saminsky, Lazare (Box 10)
  - Sams, Alfred (Box 10)
  - Sandburg, Carl (Box 10)
  - Sanwald, Marie (Box 10)
  - Sargent, Cynthia (Box 10)
  - Saroyan, Aram (Box 10)
  - Saroyan, William (Box 10)
  - Saturday Review of Literature (Box 10)
  - Savage, Naomi (Siegler) (Box 10)
  - Schaefer, Bertha (Box 10)
  - Schank, Will H. (Box 10)
  - Schapiro, J. Salwyn (Box 10)
  - Schevill, Margaret Irwin (Box 10)
  - Schirmer, G., Inc. (Box 10)
  - Schorer, Mark (Box 10)
  - Scott, Betty (Box 10)
  - Scovel, Myra (Box 10)
  - Scribner's Magazine (Box 10)
  - Seabrook, William (Box 10)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery (Box 10)
  - Seligmann, James F. (Box 10)
  - Shapiro, Karl (Box 10)
  - Shepard, Odell (Box 10)
  - Sheppard, John S. (Box 10)
  - Shientag, Bernard L. (Box 10)
  - Shipman, Louis Evan (Box 10)
  - Shively, George (Box 10)
  - Simonson, Lee (Box 10)
  - Sims, Madge R. (Box 10)
  - Sinclair, Mary Craig (Box 10)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box 10)
  - Sloan, Samuel (Box 10)
  - Sloane, T. O'Connor (Box 10)
  - Small, Barbara F. (Box 10)
  - Small, Hubert F. (Box 10)
  - Smart Set, The (Box 10)
  - Smith, George M. (Box 10)
  - Smith, Harrison (Box 10)
  - Smith, Mrs. Mark (Box 10)
  - Snell, George (Box 10)
  - Solomos, George P. (Box 10)
  - Southwest Review (Box 10)
  - Spaeth, Sigmund (Box 10)
  - Spearing, Edna M. (Box 10)
  - Speyer, Leonora (Box 10)
  - Sphinx, The (Box 10)
  - Spimgarn, Arthur B. (Box 10)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. (Box 10)
  - Spillman, Ramsay (Box 10)
  - Sporting News (Box 10)
  - Stage, The (Box 11)
  - Steible, Daniel J. (Box 11)
  - Stein and Day (Box 11)
  - Steinman, D.B. (Box 11)
  - Stern, James (Box 11)
  - Stern, James (Box 11)
  - Stern, Nathan (Box 11)
  - Steuben Glass - "Poetry in Crystal" (Box 11)
  - Stewart, Paul R. (Box 11)
  - Stone, Mary (Box 11)
  - Stone, Susan (Box 11)
  - Stony, Mary (Box 11)
  - Struther, Jan (Box 11)
  - Sullivan, A.M. (Box 11)
  - Sulloway, Alison (Box 11)
  - Summerfield, Jack D. (Box 11)
  - Swallow, Alan (Box 11)
  - Syracuse University (Box 11)
  - Tambimuttu (Box 11)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 11)
  - Tate, Marion (Box 11)
  - Taylor, Mary (Box 11)
  - Tekeyan, Charles (Box 11)
  - Templeton, Sydney (Box 11)
  - Thayer, Ellen (Box 11)
  - Thomas, Margaret L. (Box 11)
  - Thompson, Dorothy Brown (Box 11)
  - Thurber, James (Box 11)
  - Tierney, Patrick J. (Box 11)
  - Time (Box 11)
  - Tomorrow (Box 11)
  - Torrence, Ridgley (Box 11)
  - Trace, Granville (Box 11)
  - Trilling, Lionel (Box 11)
  - Troubetzkon, Amelie (Box 11)
  - Truman, David B. (Box 11)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Box 11)
  - Truth (Box 11)
  - Turnbull, Andrew (Box 11)
  - Tusiani, Joseph (Box 11)
  - Ungar, Florence (Box 11)
  - University of Kansas City Review (Box 11)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 11)
  - Van Bergh, Beatrice (Box 11)
  - Van Doren, Irita (Box 11)
  - Van Doren, Mark (Box 11)
  - Viereck, Peter (Box 11)
  - Villa, Jose Garcia (Box 11)
  - Vinal, Harold (Box 11)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 11)
  - Virginia Writers Club (Box 11)
  - Waggoner, Hyatt (Box 11)
  - Wallant, Edward Lewis (Box 11)
  - Warren, Elinor remick (Box 11)
  - Wassall, Irma (Box 11)
  - Wechsler, James (Box 11)
  - Wechsler, Louis K. (Box 11)
  - Weeks, Edward (Box 11)
  - Wells, Hilda Gaige (Box 11)
  - West, Jessamyn (Box 11)
  - Wharton, Aline Harwood (Box 11)
  - Wharton, George W. (Box 11)
  - Wheelock, John Hall (Box 11)
  - Whicher, George F. (Box 11)
  - White, E.B. (Box 11)
  - Whittlesey House (Box 11)
  - Wilbur, Richard (Box 11)
  - Williams, Elaine M. (Box 11)
  - Wilson, Rufus R. (Box 11)
  - Wimberly Lowry C. (Box 11)
  - Winship, George P. (Box 11)
  - Winslow, Clara L. (Box 11)
  - Winters, Yvor (Box 11)
  - Wisconsin Poetry Magazine (Box 11)
  - Wisdom, William B. (Box 11)
  - Wittnauer, A. (Watch Co.) (Box 11)
  - Wolfe, Don M. (Box 11)
  - Wolfe, Humbert (Box 11)
  - Wolff, Helen and Kurt (Box 11)
  - Yale Review (Box 11)
  - Young, Jefferson (Box 11)
  - Your Life (Box 11)
  - Zimmerman, Michael (Box 11)
  - Zinsser, Hans (Box 11)
  - Zusmer, Ruth (Box 11)
- Series IV: Books and Periodicals
  - Subseries IV.1: Books & Periodicals By Or With Contributions By Cane
    - Maule, Harry E. & Melville Cane, eds. The Man from Main Street: A Sinclair Lewis Reader (Box 12)
    - Paget, R.L., selected by Cap and Gown: Third Series of College Verse (Box 12)
    - Miss Read Country Bunch (Box 12)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, ed. Modern American Poetry (Box 12)
    - Tanner, William M. & Frank J. Platt My English: Book 4 (Box 12)
    - Untermeyer, Louis Doorways to Poetry (Box 12)
    - Untermeyer, Louis Poetry: Its Appreciation and Enjoyment (Box 12)
    - Gillis, Adolph & William Rose Benet, eds. Poems for Modern Youth (Box 13)
    - Gray, William S. & Lillian Gray Guidebook for Friends and Neighbors and More Friends and Neighbors (Box 13)
    - Cook, Luella B., H.A. Miller, Jr. & Walter Loban Adventures in Appreciation (Box 13)
    - Connolly, Francis The Types of Literature (Box 13)
    - Dannt, Mary, selected by Adventures into Poetry: Secondary Book IV (Box 13)
    - Doane, Pelagie, selected by Poems of Praise (Box 13)
    - Morgan, Grace, ed. Poems for Boys and Girls: Book Two (Box 13)
    - Dannt, Mary, selected by A Modern Treasury (Box 13)
    - Literature Committee of the Association for Childhood Education, selected by Sung Under the Silver Umbrella (Box 13)
    - Cane, Melville Tree in December (Box 14)
    - Hall, Lawrence S. How Thinking is Written (Box 14)
    - Grisenthwaite N., compiled by Pegasus: Three (Box 14)
    - Rittenhouse, Charles B., ed. Your Poetry Book: Five (Box 14)
    - Poetry Awards: 1951 (Box 14)
    - Eller, William, Betty Welch & Edward Gordon Introduction to Literature (Box 14)
    - Reuben, Rebecca New Ashok Readers: Book II (Box 14)
    - First, Wesley, ed. University on the Heights (Box 14)
    - Sheldon, William, Nellie Lyons & Polly Ronalt The Reading of Poetry (Box 14)
    - Rolfe, Franklin, William Davenport & Paul Bowerman The Modern Omnibus (Box 14)
    - Wolfe, Don M. Language Arts and Life Patterns (Box 15)
    - Van Doren, Mark, Arno Jewett, Margaret Early & Olga Achtenhagen Insights into Literature (Box 15)
    - Wolfe, Don M., Ruth A. Firor & Thomas Donahue The Freshman and his World (Box 15)
    - Witty, Paul A. & Alma Moore Freeland Silver Web (Box 15)
    - Wolfe, Don M. & Ellen M. Geyer Enjoying English II (Box 15)
    - Thompson, Blanche Jennings More Silver Pennies (Box 15)
    - Cane, Melville January Garden (Box 15)
    - Wilson, Rufus Rockwell, assembled by The Golden Year (Box 15)
    - White, Elizabeth, Joan Wofford & Edward Gordon Understanding Literature (Box 15)
    - Cane, Melville Behind Dark Spaces (Box 15)
    - Clymer, Eleanor, collected by Arrow Book of Funny Poems (Box 15)
    - Cargill, K.C. & K.A. Dykeman Creative English: Grade 5 (Box 16)
    - Bright, Frank F. & Ralph Potter To be an American (Box 16)
    - The Poetry Society of America Anthology (Box 16)
    - Arbuthnot, May Hill, compiled by Time for Poetry (Box 16)
    - Applegate, Mauree Winged Writing (Box 16)
    - Aked, Valerie & Margrethe Knudsen, selected by Quicksilver (Box 16)
    - Altstetter, Mabel, Elizabeth Baker & Glenwood Clark The Language We Use: Book One (Box 16)
    - Bretz, Ann Cory Profile of Poetry (Box 16)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley Braithwaite's Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1926 Yearbook of American Poets (Box 16)
    - Cane, Melville A Wider Arc (Box 17)
    - Cane, Melville Poems: New and Selected (Box 17)
    - Parker, T.H. and F.J. Teskey, compiled by It Could Happen to You (Box 17)
    - Hallmark Cards, selected by the editors of Poetry for Pleasure (Box 17)
    - Tomorrow, n.p., April 1942 (Box 17)
    - The Nation, n.p., 27 Feb 1929 (Box 17)
    - The Nation, n.p., 9 Jan 1929 (Box 17)
    - The New English Weekly, n.p., 19 May 1932 (Box 17)
    - Life, n.p., 18 June 1925 (Box 17)
    - Cameron, Jack and Emma Plattor The Leaf not the Tree (Box 17)
    - Arbuthnot, May Hill and Shelton L. Root, Jr., compiled by Time for Poetry (Box 17)
    - McInnes, John & Jean Wheatley Teacher's Guidebook for Hockey Cards and Hopscotch (Box 18)
    - McFarland, Philip, Melinda Kavanagh, William Jamison & Morse Peckham Moments in Literature (Box 18)
    - Wolfe, Don M. & Josie Lewis Enjoying English: 10 (Box 18)
    - Wolfe, Don M. & Josie Lewis Enjoying English: Teacher's Edition (Box 18)
    - Jones, Daisy & Louis Cooper From Actors to Astronauts (Box 18)
    - Lamb, P., G.O. Aubrey, W.J. Crocken & R.J. McDonald Growing Up with English: Book 4 (Box 18)
    - BBC Radio for Schools Stories and Rhymes, n.p., Autumn 1971 (Box 18)
    - Seaburg, Carl, ed. Great Occasions (Box 18)
    - Larrick, Nancy, ed. Piping Down the Valleys Wild (Box 18)
    - Clymer, Theodore & Virginia Jones Seven is Magic (Box 18)
    - Shane, Harold, Florence Ferris, Mary York & Edward Keener Using Good English: 5 (Box 18)
    - Wolfe, Don M. A Study of Poetry (Box 19)
    - Laughlin, James, ed. New Directions in Prose and Poetry: 12 (Box 19)
    - Gordon, Edward, Betty Welch & William Eller Introduction to Literature (Box 19)
    - McFarland, Philip, Linda Konichek, Jeanne King, William Jamison & Morse Peckham Explorations in Literature (Box 19)
    - Brewton, Sara and John, compiled by America Forever New (Box 19)
    - Cane, Melville The First Firefly (Box 19)
    - Burns, R.L. & R.F. Thomas The First Firefly (Box 19)
    - Brash, J.G.S. & E.H. Winter Poems to Appreciate (Box 19)
    - Untermeyer, Louis & Carter Davidson Poetry: Its Appreciation and Enjoyment (Box 19)
    - Putnam's Monthly, n.p., March 1907 (Box 20)
    - Columbia Alumni News, n.p., 2 April 1920 (Box 20)
    - Poet, n.p., Jan 1973 (Box 20)
    - Clymer, Theodore, Leo Ruth, Peter Evanechko & Julia Higgs Awakenings (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Winter 1972-1973 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Spring 1970 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Autumn 1973 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Winter 1970-1971 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Summer 1972 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Winter 1973-1974 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Summer 1964 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Spring 1971 (Box 20)
    - American Scholar, n.p., Autumn 1957 (Box 20)
    - Field, Andrew, ed. Pages from Tarusa (Box 20)
    - Cotton, Michael & Marian, eds. Soundings: A Poetry Workshop (Box 20)
    - School Journal, n.p., Spring 1957 (Box 20)
    - Columbia Law Alumni Bulletin, n.p., Winter 1970 (Box 21)
    - Maule, Harr E. & Melville Cane, eds. A Sinclair Lewis Reader: The Man from Main Street (Box 21)
    - The Forge: A Journal of Verse, n.p., Summer 1927 (Box 21)
    - Voices, n.p., Spring 1937 (Box 21)
    - Voices, n.p., Dec 1927 (Box 21)
    - Contemporary Verse, n.p., April 1926 (Box 21)
    - Gregory, George P. Environmental Concerns: The Nation (Box 21)
    - The American Scholar, n.p., Spring 1974 (Box 21)
    - Voyages, n.p., Winter 1970 (Box 21)
    - Moore, Lilian, selected by Each in a Different Voice (Box 21)
    - The Poetry Society of America Bulletin, n.p., April 1965 (Box 21)
    - Baron, Henry J., Bruce Hekman & Daniel Vander Ark, eds. Touchstones Around Us (Box 21)